This is your chance to escape from here.
But if you do that,
you must not show yourself to them.
For sure,
your grandfather and your daddy will look for you.
Why do you have a drawing of Mr. Samuel?
- Samuel?
Yes, he often comes here.
That's Mr. Samuel. Samuel Almero.
You know, Lorenzo, it's all your fault.
You're the reason why Florence is rebelling.
Don't interfere with family matters.
Your anger won't help right now.
What's important is
we have to figure out where Florence went.
I think I have an idea where she went.
I do hope Florence is here.
I hope she went back to our house.
Because if that happens,
I will never give her back to you.
Even if you kill me.
You can never get my daughter back.
The reason why I brought them here,
is because I told them
to talk about their plan.
- Plan?
- What plan?
We plan to go to a faraway place.
To elope and live together.
Away from all these problems.
What?
Maybe Alyanna escaped from you that night.
She knew the situation was dangerous,
that's why she couldn't do anything,
but protect her daughter!
Well, I didn't eat.
What do you mean you didn't eat?
I ordered three cups of rice,
but you took another one.
If you think about it.
Wait, I feel dizzy.
Oh no, that's what I'm telling you.
Okay, let's drink medicine later.
What medicine?
Well, I'll take care of it.
Mister, have you seen a woman pass by here?
No.
No?
Okay, thank you.
What's his problem?
- Did you hear that?
- Was that you?
That's not me.
- What was that?
Oh no. Is that a cricket?
- Something is moving at the back.
- Huh?
What's that?
Enough with this madness!
This is clearly a blatant attempt
to tear my family apart.
Let's leave.
Lorenzo!
- Hey, wait.
- It's okay.
It's okay. Lorenzo...
If you love Alyanna,
you will find out the truth.
Because only the truth can protect Florence.
They really have the nerve.
I'm the one who's being reasonable.
I'm the one who's being accused of something.
- Lorenzo!
- Is it true?
Were you there when Alyanna was killed?
Lorenzo, come on. Do you believe them more?
Answer me!
Is it true? Why can't you answer?
It's a simple yes or no question.
Were you there when my wife was killed?
Do you believe them more than me, Lorenzo?
Do you see me as your brother?
That's enough!
Let's go home first.
Let's find out the root of all of this.
If Federico is telling the truth...
you have a lot of explaining to do, Samuel!
Dad? Dad?
Baste! Baste, start the car.
Come on, get inside the car.
Really?
You will really tolerate their plan to elope?
I mean, why not?
God gave us free will,
and what better way to use our free will,
than to spend the rest of our lives
with the person we love.
- That's right.
Right?
Cheers, guys.
I can't believe that Nero is capable,
unlike other guys that I know
who are quiet when it comes to romance.
Are you challenging me?
Nero, I'm so happy for you.
That is why I now know
why Antonia was so obsessed with you.
Ouch, Camille.
I wonder when I can graduate
from your "crazy ex-girlfriend" punchline.
- Well...
- No, but I really do agree. I'm impressed.
And if ever things don't work out...
I can definitely be next in line, Nero.
That's okay, bro.
- Just joking.
- My gosh.
Who said romance is dead?
Why?
Do you want us to elope too?
- Of course not.
- Oh my gosh!
Exactly the point.
Eloping is the most stupid thing to do.
Why do they have to elope?
Just face the problem
and find ways to keep loving each other.
Running away is the most selfish thing
one can do.
That's what you get from watching K-dramas.
It's all romance and thrill.
You're not thinking.
- You're such a killjoy, Bro.
- Bitter.
Boo, Tristan.
Maybe you should take a page
from Nero's playbook.
And learn
that sometimes, life can be about love.
You know, you should stop picking on Tristan.
I was being impulsive.
I hated the idea that everything I want,
all my decisions,
are controlled by my new family.
What I should be feeling right now
is I should be thrilled
because I just entered
into my first relationship.
Your first and last relationship.
Oh my gosh.
There!
But Tristan is right, Nero.
I got carried away by my emotions.
I couldn't get what I want,
that's why I escaped and ran away.
If you didn't see me,
maybe I'd be in Baguio by now.
But now that I get to spend time
with all of you,
even for a short time...
I was able to think.
You're right, Tristan.
Running away is very selfish.
And you can't easily escape
all these complications.
It's difficult, but I have to.
And it seems that's what I need to do.
To face all my problems.
So...
Nero?
I'm sorry, but it seems
we're not pushing through.
Let's cancel our plans
of living in a nipa hut...
by the beach with our pet dog and cat.
You know I will support you
in all of your decisions.
You know what this means, right?
If you go back to your dad,
he'll probably take you to the States.
Guys, this is probably the last time
we'll be able to spend time with Florence.
Last?
As in final, final?
Yes.
No way.
Dad, take this.
I'm sorry for what happened earlier.
I just couldn't control myself.
Tell me, Lorenzo...
Do you honestly believe Samuel
has something to do with Alyanna's death?
You know...
I don't know what to think.
It seems Federico's accusation is absurd.
I can't explain it, Dad, but...
the accusation?
It all made sense to me.
Samuel is your brother!
You're suspecting a family member.
I know.
That's why I wanted him to deny it.
I wanted him to tell me to my face,
that all the accusations against him
were not true.
For whatever reason, Dad...
I have a strong feeling,
Samuel has something to do with
what happened to my wife and daughter.
Talk to Baste.
Do it discreetly.
I don't want anyone to hear
or know what we're about to do.
I want Samuel investigated.
I want to know everything about him.
Dig up everything that he is hiding.
And I want you to talk to Federico as well.
Find out all the details
you can get from him.
And then I want you to talk to our people.
And I want you to have them
interview everybody,
all the people in that area.
If it's true
that someone saw or recognized Samuel...
If it's proven
that Samuel has something
to do with Alyanna's death...
I'm going to make sure that he pays for it.
Are you sure
it was Samuel who you remembered?
He sure is, Don Ferell,
because Federico hadn't met Samuel...
but he was able to describe
and draw the face of that animal.
You were able to draw him? Let me see.
Where?
What?
How can this be Samuel?
Babycakes, turn the page.
I wasn't the only one who recognized him.
A lot of people saw and recognized him
in the area where Alyanna was killed.
Why did he flaunt his face there?
If just in case I'd committed a crime,
I won't go back there.
And why would you commit a crime?
I said just in case.
I think he was looking for the baby.
He was looking for Florence.
It just so happened
that Alyanna was able to hide the baby.
That's what we thought too.
I think he's using the kid for the ransom.
Imagine that. He is fooling his own father.
We cannot go by assumptions.
Serafica, call our people.
I want a legal team assembled.
And also get a good investigator.
That Samuel Almero
should be investigated properly.
I want to have correct evidence
that we can show to Don Almero
the next time I see him.
Yes, Sir. I'll do that first thing tomorrow.
I'll get to the bottom of this.
I'll make sure that Florence is safe.
It's a blessing
that Florence ran away from them.
That's right.
At least now, she is far from Samuel.
She is safe.
Maybe she's not only safe...
but safer?
Safest, safer-est.
- That's what I'm saying.
- That's it.
You keep saying it over and over.
Yes.
And where have you all been?
A lot of things are happening here
and you managed to go out and have fun.
Relax.
We didn't go out and have fun, Ms. Serafica.
Actually, we met up with Florence.
Florence?
Where is she?
Don't worry, Auntie. She's okay.
Relax.
She was planning to run away,
but we were able to convince her.
She's on her way back to the Almeros.
What?
Did I say something?
I'm hopeful that they will listen to me.
I will try to convince them
not to send me to the States.
What if they won't agree?
Well, then...
I will follow your advice.
Sometimes love is enduring, so...
I'll just have to endure.
I may be far from you, but...
my love won't stop.
Don't worry, Florence.
I'll convince Grandpa Garp
to let me transfer to the States.
Are you sure?
There are a lot of English speakers there.
I will always be true to my promise.
To be always by your side.
Wow.
Please, take it easy with your sweetness.
I'm already diabetic, won't you pity me?
I've been with you both for a long time.
Grandpa is calling.
Hello?
Nero, listen.
Don't ever let Florence
go back to the Almeros.
Grandpa? Hello?
Her life is in danger.
Her uncle, Samuel, he's the killer.
What did Grandpa say? Is he looking for us?
My phone suddenly died.
Maybe he's worried.
Maybe he's been calling me.
Wait, I'll just get my phone in the car.
Wait, let's take Florence home first.
Okay.
Well, just tell them what happened,
so they will always be updated
on the latest showbiz events and happenings.
Uncle Samuel?
Uncle Samuel!
Florence.
What happened to you?
This? Well, this is nothing.
How about you? Why are you still here?
I already helped you escape.
Why did you come back?
Didn't you miss me?
Don't you want me here?
Don't you want my scrambled eggs anymore,
and the food I cook for you?
Nero, Tristan, he is Uncle Samuel.
My favorite uncle.
Well, he is my only uncle,
but that won't diminish
the favor I hold for him.
Is there a problem?
Nothing...
It's...
your Grandpa Roger.
He had a heart attack.
He's in the hospital right now.
That's why...
you need to go with me.
Come on, let's go to him.
We'll go with you.
- Okay.
- Let's go. Hurry.
Still nothing?
Tristan is still not answering.
Dencio, Iking, let's go to them.
- Try again.
- Come on. Let's go!
- Take care.
- Just stay here.
You are more needed here.
Uncle Samuel, what happened to Grandpa?
Why did he suffer a heart attack?
Is it because I ran away?
This is my fault.
Florence, Florence.
It's not your fault.
And I'm sure he'll be okay.
What if he's not?
I can't forgive myself
if something bad happens to him.
Florence...
Nero is right.
Don't worry.
Wait, why weren't you with them
in the hospital?
Nothing...
I needed to go home.
I needed to get some things.
Wait.
Where is this hospital you're saying?
Just over there.
It's the Mary Grace Hospital.
Wait, we're not going there.
This is going out of Levante.
Get off the car.
Uncle Samuel, why do you have that?
Don't ask too many questions.
Get off the car!
Get down!
- What?
- Don't move!
Do you want to fight back?
I said get off the car. Get off the car!
I said get off.
Stay here.
I said, here.
Uncle Samuel, what's this?
Why are you doing this?
It's clear.
He's planning something bad.
Shut up, kid.
Where is Grandpa Roger?
Don't worry about your grandpa.
He's safe.
But you know what?
All of this wouldn't have happened...
if not for your father figure, Federico.
I don't understand.
What does Father have to do with this?
He remembered and saw what happened...
the night Alyanna died.
And he's saying that I killed your mother.
But I think there's nothing I can do.
I can't get away with
the secrets that I've kept.
Because your grandfather and daddy...
are having me investigated.
I'm sure...
your Grandpa Garpidio
will dig up all my secrets.
Tomorrow or the day after...
they'll find out about my secret.
Mister, what's happening?
I don't know.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry, Celestina.
Mommy has to go.
Just stay here first.
I love you so much. I love you, Celestina.
Let's go, you're sleepy.
Your head hurts, let's go home.
- Let's go.
- I feel dizzy.
Mister?
Have you seen a woman pass by here?
No.
No?
Okay, thank you.
What? He suddenly appeared.
Samuel!
Samuel, please.
Don't do this.
Why are you inside the car?
And not Lorenzo?
Alyanna...
I have to do this.
Because you'll tell them everything I did.
What did Lorenzo do to you?
Why do you have to hurt him?
Samuel, Lorenzo is your brother.
We're one family.
Family?
Are you really a part of my family?
Are you really all my family?
As long as Lorenzo's alive...
I will never get what I deserve.
Whatever I do...
Daddy only loves him.
Whatever sacrifices I do...
I know he will still get everything.
Don't do this, Samuel.
I'm begging you.
You're not a bad person.
Don't let that anger in your heart
eat you up.
Please, don't.
I'm sorry, Alyanna...
But don't worry.
I will look for Celestina.
- No...
- I will always protect her.
That I was the one who killed your mother.
That's why when I saw you having a hard time
under Lorenzo's care.
Florence, I helped you so you can escape.
So, you can be free, right?
Right?
Because that's what I promised Alyanna.
So that somehow...
I can pay...
for what I did to her.
Is this your way of protecting me?
Florence...
I will not hurt you.
Don't worry.
But don't you dare
do something I wouldn't like.
Because if not...
I might not be able
to fulfill what I promised your mother.
Florence, I just need you, so I can escape.
So I can get money
from your grandfather and your dad.
Because I want to start anew...
and live far away from all of you.
Good thing you brought a Ferell with you.
I'll earn more with this.
You will not win.
Wherever you go...
you'll pay for all your sins.
Why?
What do you know about my sins?
What do you know?
You're so young.
Do you want me to make you an example?
If all my plans don't push through...
the Ferells and Almeros will pay me
a huge amount of money.
Move over, Florence.
- No, Uncle Samuel. Don't.
- Move over, Florence. Move.
- Tristan!
- Tristan, don't!
- Uncle Samuel, stop it!
Enough, please.
- Tristan!
- Tristan, don't!
Tristan!
- Tristan!
Tristan...
Don't worry.
You're safe now.
Tristan?
Hey...
- Tristan? Hey!
- Help!
- Help us!
- Tristan, hey!
- Tristan, wake up!
Help!
Help us!
- Hey, wake up!
- Help!
Florence...
is this okay?
- Just one more, Mother.
- Okay.
Where is Dencio?
- Thanks, dear.
- Where are the Guimaras mangoes?
Florence, we have a problem.
We have a problem with the mangoes.
Why?
Don't tell me those are not Guimaras Mangoes.
Tristan only wants Guimaras Mangoes,
the sweetest mangoes in the whole world.
The universe, rather.
Of course, let me finish first.
These are Guimaras Mangoes,
but our problem is
we might just do two mango pies.
Because on our way back here,
Iking ate the mangoes.
Originally, we had two baskets.
Now we only have one.
I can't stop myself. It's delicious.
As a matter of fact,
there's a rumor...
that Guimaras Mangoes are served
in the Buckingham Palace of Queen Elizabeth.
If the Queen ate the mangoes,
what more than I,
who's just a commoner?
Okay, that's enough,
but you're no longer allowed
to eat mango pie.
- There you go.
- Fair enough.
By the way Florence,
you have to make sure
that your pie is crusty and not crunchy.
That's how Tristan wants it, okay?
Wait.
What's the difference?
That's just the same, right?
Because the sound is crunchy
when what you're eating is crusty.
But it seems it's not okay
if it's not crunchy and crusty?
Mother, I'll take care of that
because I know the secret
to making it crusty but not crunchy.
There's your mango pie.
I've perfected that already.
Enjoy it over there.
Tristan, now that you're there,
you have no excuse.
Be with your grandmother.
Remember, we're the Ferells.
How about you, guys?
Don't you have something to say to that guy?
Bro, don't worry.
I made sure to delete your browsing history
so no one would know
what videos you are watching.
Bro, you're a fool.
I owe GU a huge amount of money,
and they're asking me to pay...
because you ate a lot of brownies.
Don't worry, Bro. Camille is perfectly fine.
Aira, Lina, and Antonia are always with her.
And I'm making sure
she has someone to talk to.
Don't worry. We'll take care of it.
Say hi to dad.
I'm sorry.
Just be patient with his jokes.
And please tell him that we're okay here...
and that there's no need to worry.
No one needs to knock on my heart.
It's now open to love.
Tristan, my child.
Thank you so much for all the memories.
Tristan...
I'll take care of your car.
Tristan, I'm sorry
I ate your Guimaras Mangoes.
I will miss your muscles.
Tristan...
I will miss your mango pies.
Sir Tristan...
we'll always remember you.
With my first bite of mango pie,
that's for you.
Tristan...
I'll consider it a huge debt of gratitude
for saving my daughter.
Thank you so much, Tristan.
I will now take care of your family.
You're open to love?
Shouldn't be that closed already?
Am I not enough?
It's enough...
but you're leaving.
That's why I'm keeping it open,
waiting for your return.
I'm sorry, Nero,
but I really need to do this.
Actually, Daddy said
I can stay and continue with Gyronella.
But I thought,
maybe this is the perfect time and opportunity
to go abroad first.
He also promised that he'll stop working,
so he can have time for me.
So, we have more time to bond.
I can get to know him better,
and I'll ask him to tell me
about his love story with Mommy.
What about Mother and Father?
I want to bring them, but...
it's their decision not to go.
I've been with them for 18 years,
that's why it's not bad
if I'm with Daddy in the meantime next year.
I'm sorry, Nero.
This is my decision.
I need to complete my story.
It doesn't matter how long it takes.
I will wait for you, Florence.
I will wait for you, until the end of time.
Wow. You're an English poet now.
But once I'm ready, I'll come back.
And if you will really wait for me,
you'll have my heart completely.
It should be.
A white guy might flirt with you.
If so, I will beat him.
Wow.
Violent.
I'm just telling you.
Who knows?
When I come back,
I will not only give you my heart...
What else?
Who knows? I'm ready to give you my...
Next time...
you won't have a choice.
Our lips might touch.
I'm not yet ready.
- Next time?
- Next time.
Next time, when I come back.
You will no longer have a choice.
I will delay my return.
No, please don't.
They said it's hard to say goodbye.
What they didn't know is
that waiting is more difficult than goodbye.
They said it's hard to say goodbye.
What they didn't know is
that waiting is more difficult than goodbye.
- Hi!
- Hello.
- I miss you, guys.
- Hello. Hey.
- Hey, handsome man!
- Hey!
Hi!
You need to smile and pretend
that every day that passes by...
it's okay not to see you.
That I can face everything without you.
But it's hard, Florence.
It's difficult
because of the memories you left.
The stories...
laughter...
goofing around moments...
and all the scenes remind me
of how we were once happy.
And convinced us that it's possible...
to make the world more colorful
every time I'm with you.
The ironic thing, Florence,
is that these memories
that make my longing deeper...
are the same memories that comfort me.
And it makes me believe.
It gives me hope...
that this chapter is
not the end of our story.
As we turn another page in our story,
what's waiting for me is a world
where our hands are holding each other.
We're together,
helping each other complete our story.
I cannot wait, Florence...
I can't wait to see you again.
To hug you.
I cannot wait
to spend the rest of my life with you.
I will wait...
for your return.
But it's hard, Florence.
It's so difficult without you.
But don't worry.
I'm always looking for a way...
to relieve the sadness and longing.
But the truth is,
you can't relieve the longing.
We're just convincing ourselves...
that tomorrow or the day after...
all the heaviness in our hearts will go away.
I pray that one morning I'll wake up...
and that my beloved has returned.
And we can start again with a new chance...
to love.
Hello, Nero! I'm back!
Florence?
I'm just happy that you're here.
So, let's see each other tomorrow?
Go ahead and end the call.
You end it first.
Hey, the last time, it was me.
Then you do it again.
You're unfair.
Hurry.
- Go ahead and end the call.
- You go first.
Don't be a cheater, Florence.
Okay, here it goes. Bye.
Bye-bye.
Tristan?